

HOH KOK YOUNG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Graduated in the software engineering field at APU, awarded as the best student, and has been specialising web applications development ever since. Desirous of thought-provoking challenges and incessant exploration in new insights, especially back-end development and solution architect techniques.

+6012-342 9617

kokyoung1520@gmail.com

github.com/hohkokyoung

in linkedin.com/in/hohkokyoung

hohkokyoung.github.io/e-resume



EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering

Dual Degree | Asia Pacific University & Staffordshire University | Aug 2019 - Dec 2021

First Class Honours & Best Student Award

CGPA: 3.93

Diploma in ICT (Software Engineering)

Asia Pacific University | May 2017 - May 2019 CGPA: 3.97

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Backend Engineer

RedSquare Software | Aug 2021 - Present

Achievement: Contributed significantly to a medium-sized CMS/E-commerce web & mobile application with a comprehensive reporting dashboard for the ChinaPress clients. @ mywheels.my

- Develop and integrate numerous APIs to accommodate different website displays.
- Document important business operations and code functions to ease future implementation and communication.
- Liaise with project managers to ensure feasible yet satisfactory feature expectations.
- Seek advice and insights from seniors regularly to make sure proper programming principles and practices are upheld.
- Propose appropriate software diagramming practices to streamline communication between the team.
- Exercise hybrid methodology including Kanban and Scrum with retrospective suggestions to further refine development process.
- Develop multiple background tasks to automate interval updates.
- Provide upper management from time to time on several solutions, detailed with respective pros and cons to mission-critical problems.

Achievement: Took over and single-handedly completed a half-finished online courses booking web application catered to SMEs using Django, as well as AJAX to improve overall user experience. Capedia.com

- Develop the application thoroughly using MVC principles.
- Refactor old codebase to prevent wasteful resources on subsequent implementation.
- Make decisions regularly on selecting the most pragmatic implementation that conforms to the technical requirements and tight schedule.

Software Engineer Intern

RedSquare Software | Jul 2020 - Nov 2020

Achievement: Learned and helped develop a mobile-focused application designed to gather online talents and entertainers, built using React Native.

- Integrate several APIs to respective mobile pages.
- Improve application performance and user experience significantly by incorporating transitions and animations, reducing component rendering, applying pagination and segregating API calls.
- Document user manual to properly guide the application usage to the clients.

PERSONAL PROJECT

Cyberbullying Detection System using Machine Learning

Final Year Project

Project: A web-based system that detects code-switching (English & Malay) cyberbullying messages on Twitter in Malaysia using sentiment analysis, allowing government agencies and NGOs to monitor them.

- Clean dataset through preprocessing the data, removing the stopwords and lemmatizing the words.
- Perform exploratory data analysis to identify outliers and imbalance of dataset.
- Tokenize, train, test and compare models built using machine learning and deep learning algorithms.
- Scrape, classify, calculate and illustrate cyberbullying tweets in interactive graphs on the website, including bar and map chart.

